Alec Hodgkinson

DEEP LEARNING ENGINEER

□(+1) 650-255-2445 | Modgka@gmail.com | Alechodgkinson.com | Dodgka | Dodgka

Summary_

A deep learning engineer with experience rapid prototyping, implementing state of the art models, and writing technical reports. I like to work on cool projects which means I touch every part of the technology stack nearly every day.

Education

Rensselaer Polytechnic University

Aug 2013 - Dec 2016

B.S. IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS, MINOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Experience

Panasonic Beta Mar 2018 - Present

ACTION GENOME HOME, PROJECT LEAD

- · Managing activities in a team of seven, including engineering, process development, and data recording, and proposal writing.
- Developed hardware prototype using Raspberry Pi and a variety of sensors. Wrote custom firmware to communicate between the Pi and sensors over I2C Bus
- · Wrote software to cleanly record and package video and sensor data into a video container for easy distribution.
- Developed a Flask-based front-end for recording synchronized data across multiple sensor suites, speeding up recording time by 50x.
- Wrote proposal for a workshop at the ECCV2020 conference.

DOORGYM: A SCALABLE DOOR OPENING ENVIRONMENT AND BASELINE AGENT, PROJECT LEAD

- Developed initial proof of concept for door opening simulation.
- Developed a novel CNN-based vision pipeline for regressing 3D door knob location from multiple views. Achieved an accuracy of ±1.7 cm in simulation, accurate enough for an agent to open a door.
- Transferred vision neural network trained in simulation to real doorknobs with an accuracy of ±4.95cm.
- Performed ablation tests to verify the necessity of each component in the vision network pipeline.
- Created infrastructure for interfacing neural networks with the Baxter Robot platform.

Panasonic Silicon Valley Labs

Mar 2017 - Mar 2018

DEEP LEARNING ENGINEER

- Developed a novel post-processing filter for image codecs resulting in a 20%+ reduction in bitrate.
- Implemented end-to-end deep learning models for image compression using Tensorflow.
- Evaluated and adapted state of the art deep learning models for alleviating catastrophic forgetting in neural networks.
- Developed face tracking/identification software for a robotic platform running in real time at 30 FPS.
- Authored technical papers and descriptions for three individual patents.
- Developed proof of concept demonstration using deep learning based monocular image height estimation running on a Raspberry Pi for presentation to CEO.
- Developed a gesture detection model and API for use in a smart home setting.

Junior.io Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

DEEP LEARNING INTERN

 Architected the backend of a content based music recommender system for an open space environment using a PostgreSQL database, the Spotify API, and git for source control.

• Built a neural network to classify user preferences based on previous listening habits in Keras.

Projects_

Pixel Recursive Super Resolution Implementation

PERSONAL Mar 2017 - Apr 2017

• Implemented "Pixel Recursive Super Resolution" using Tensorflow, to "enhance" low resolution images by adding missing details to generate higher resolution images.

• Reproduced results of the original authors using multiple different metrics such as PSNR and SSIM.

Programming Python, JavaScript, C++, LaTeX

Machine Learning PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, NumPy, OpenCV

Web Flask, HTML5, CSS3, React, P5.js

Other Technologies Git, Docker, AWS, ZeroMQ

APRIL 28, 2020 1